Contact

ricardo.jorgdealmeid@gmail.

www.linkedin.com/in/ricardo-jorgede-almeida-559a1153 (LinkedIn) www.behance.net/ ricardojorgealmeida (Other) www.facebook.com/ dramasdeumpublicitariodesempregac (Other)

Top Skills

Creative Strategy
Advertising
Concept Development

Languages

English

Honors-Awards

Gold Ativation & Events

Silver

Silver

Bronze

Honorable Mention

Ricardo Jorge de Almeida

Imaginador Profissional Always Draw

Never Even
Lisbon

Summary

Born with cartoons in my heart and comedy in my head, never once I thought: let's do advertising! The dream was to be a cartoonist/comediant. But hey, 14 years have past and it's still working, so I guess I'm doing something right

Experience

TORKE+CC

Creative Strategist & Project Leader October 2016 - Present (3 years 11 months)

MUSTARD - A NEW LEVEL

Creative Strategist & Copywriter | Social Media Manager October 2014 - October 2016 (2 years 1 month)

Lisbon Area, Portugal

- Development of the agency's rebranding with the new signature A New Level as a way to achieve a new level of awareness.
- Worked both as strategist and creative copywriter in a great deal of new business projects.
- Teamed up with the agency's Creative Director, Rui Pica. A relationship with
 4 years now, that, more than colleagues, made us friends.
- In 2015 we started working with many new clients with standard fees (a new business step for Mustard): Volvo Cars, José Maria da Fonseca, Ale-Hop, The Navigator Company.
- Social Media Managing and development of Ale-Hop's voice on social media
- Facebook and Instagram.
- Won the agency's first award Gold for Activation & Events at Prémios Lusos
- for Volvo Cars at the Volvo Ocean Race in 2015.

BUZZit - Brands Amplifier Creative Strategist & Copywriter

January 2013 - October 2014 (1 year 10 months)

Lisbon Area, Portugal

- Started as a copywriter, since this was a new agency, and later became
 more personal with strategy and creative thinking with all of the agency's group
 activity: The Shop. This included Buzzit (brand activation) and Addiction (ATL
 & BTL).
- With its growth I started working as a Creative Supervisor as a way to help our Executive Creative Director.
- Worked with brands like Sonae, Compal, SIC, Crédito Agrícola, Nestlé and many others, from brand activation, to events to Below and Above the Line Campaigns.

Velvet Design e Publicidade Creative Strategist & Copywriter April 2012 - October 2012 (7 months)

- I was in charge of all strategy and creative thinking and copywriting, working side by side with the Creative Director.
- Main projects include Fnac with BTL & ATL campaigns and FOX Channels with brand activation, events and ATL communication.
- Proud of achieving the agency's first award at the Meios & Publicidade Awards.

Cabracega - Experience Design Studio Freelance Creative March 2012 - April 2012 (2 months)

Worked as a freelance creative for an online campaign for MEO.

Strat

Creative Strategist & Copywriter and Social Media Manager December 2008 - March 2012 (3 years 4 months)

- Started as an intern and made my way through copywriting, strategic planning, trendhunting and "idea man".
- In charge of the agency's digital platforms, such as Facebook and the blog Stratum, with all of it's contents.
- Worked with site development, strategy, insight development, BTL & ATL campaigns, social media, design projects and brand activation.
- My life as a strategic thinker began here, working both as a planner and creative copywriter in many projects.
- Achieved a great number of awards working with a Creative Director that was, and still is, an inspiration: Daniel Palma (currently at JWT Portugal).

• The brands: Super Bock, Hyundai, CTT, Robbialac, Ciência Viva, Bosch, Tivoli Hotels, Pingo Doce, Fanta.

Young & Rubicam
Junior Copywriter
July 2008 - December 2008 (6 months)

• A classic copywriter period that was a truly learning experience, working with brands like BMW, Hyundai, BBVA and many others.

Torke Creative August 2007 - July 2008 (1 year) Lisboa

- This was the beginning for me. Not only on a professional level, but as a way of thinking. Torke was the first Guerrilla Agency in Portugal and that kind of approach was crucial for my development as a creative, as I learned to see everything with a different perspective.
- My first award came with the guerrilla campaign for Dexter's Season 2 premiere on Fox.
- Worked with Fox Channels, Peugeot, NOS, Sagres.
- As to this day Torke is a major influence in my professional life and more than an agency, it was a school of originality.

Inédito Comunicação e Design Junior Freelance Copywriter July 2007 - July 2007 (1 month)

Cheyenne Retail Salesperson October 2005 - May 2007 (1 year 8 months) Loures, Lisboa, Portugal

PT Contact Telecommunications Operator April 2003 - May 2005 (2 years 2 months) Lisboa

Feira Nova Salesperson November 2001 - June 2002 (8 months) Loures, Lisboa, Portugal

Education

Escola Superior de Comunicação Social Licenciatura, Publicidade · (2003 - 2008)

Escrever Escrever Workshops · (2008 - 2008)

Liceu José Afonso Ensino Secundário, Artes · (1998 - 2001)